=Within The Grip=
=داخل القبضة=
=Episode 10=
=الحلقة 10=
(Zhaoxi is Dead)
(مات تشاوشي)
You paint the plum blossoms so well, dear.
أنت ترسم أزهار البرقوق حسنًا يا عزيزي.
You like them, dear?
هل تحبهم يا عزيزي؟
Master.
يتقن.
How did it go?
كيف سارت الأمور؟
No one approached that room in the past three days.
لم يقترب أحد من تلك الغرفة في الأيام الثلاثة الماضية.
The stone chest remains closed.
يظل الصندوق الحجري مغلقًا.
I thought the contact hadn't arrived.
اعتقدت أن الاتصال لم يصل.
Fortunately, you sprinkled butterfly lure powder on the ledger.
لحسن الحظ، كنت رشها مسحوق إغراء الفراشة على الدفتر.
I released the silver butterfly when it was agitated.
لقد أطلقت الفراشة الفضية عندما كان مضطربا.
(It led me to the Right Chancellor's mansion.)
(لقد قادني إلى قصر المستشار الأيمن.)
Shall we wrap it up, Master?
هل يجب أن ننهي الأمر يا معلم؟
Not yet.
ليس بعد.
Didn't you see someone near the secret chamber?
ألم ترى أحدا بالقرب من الغرفة السرية؟
I'll keep an eye on that.
سأراقب ذلك.
One more thing.
شيء آخر.
I ran into Miss Xuanji's subordinates on my way back.
لقد واجهت مرؤوسي الآنسة Xuanji في طريق عودتي.
They said she wanted to see you
قالوا إنها تريد رؤيتك
at Zuixian Building right now
في مبنى Zuixian الآن
to tell you something.
لأقول لك شيئا.
Zuixian Building?
مبنى زويكسيان؟
(Zuixian Building)
(مبنى زويكسيان)
- Sister. - Welcome.
- أخت. - مرحباً.
So this is Zuixian Building?
إذن هذا هو مبنى Zuixian؟
It's been so long since I last saw you.
لقد مر وقت طويل منذ أن رأيتك آخر مرة.
Yuluo.
يولو.
I've missed you so much.
لقد اشتقت لك كثيرا.
He invited us here and ditched us?
لقد دعانا إلى هنا وتخلى عنا؟
Exactly.
بالضبط.
What are you doing here?
ما الذي تفعله هنا؟
To see someone.
لرؤية شخص ما.
Yuluo.
يولو.
Physician Qin, Xuanji Pavilion, Zuixian Building.
الطبيب تشين، جناح Xuanji، مبنى Zuixian.
I don't know what you're after,
لا أعرف ما الذي تسعى إليه،
but you can bring me along. I can protect you.
ولكن يمكنك أن تأخذني معك. أستطيع حمايتك.
I also heard about the burglary at Xuanji Pavilion last night.
وسمعت أيضاً عن عملية السطو في Xuanji Pavilion الليلة الماضية.
But I never stepped out of my courtyard all night.
لكنني لم أخرج قط من فناء منزلي طوال الليل.
Are you suspecting me or trying to probe?
هل تشك بي أو محاولة التحقيق؟
I...
أنا...
Yuluo.
يولو.
You know that's not what I meant.
أنت تعلم أن هذا ليس ما أقصده.
Guards. Arrest them.
حراس. القبض عليهم.
Go.
يذهب.
Stop.
قف.
Are you alright? Are you hurt?
هل أنت بخير؟ هل تأذيت؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
He's injured.
لقد أصيب.
You seem to be in high spirits.
يبدو أنك في حالة معنوية عالية.
When will you play chess with your eldest brother?
متى ستلعب الشطرنج؟ مع أخيك الأكبر؟
If you merely want to play chess,
إذا كنت تريد فقط لعب الشطرنج،
surely many people in this courtyard would oblige.
بالتأكيد كثير من الناس في هذا الفناء سوف تلزم.
Where is the death guard you always keep by your side?
أين حارس الموت هل تبقي بجانبك دائما؟
You truly don't know where she went?
أنت حقا لا تعرف أين ذهبت؟
He's a grown man. A small cut won't kill him.
إنه رجل بالغ. جرح صغير لن يقتله
Assassins don't come here for no reason.
القتلة لا يأتون إلى هنا بدون سبب.
I'll look into everyone who came.
سأنظر في كل من جاء.
Why did you two come here today?
لماذا أتيتما إلى هنا اليوم؟
Didn't you invite me over?
لم تدعوني إلى هنا؟
Me?
أنا؟
How would I know?
كيف أعرف؟
What brings you to the Fufeng Pavilion?
ما الذي جاء بك إلى جناح فوفينغ؟
If this is merely a casual visit,
إذا كانت هذه مجرد زيارة عادية،
I'm afraid I can't entertain you due to my poor health.
أخشى أنني لا أستطيع الترفيه عنك بسبب صحتي السيئة.
Xuanji caught some assassins in her courtyard.
قبض Xuanji على بعض القتلة في فناءها.
Was she hurt?
هل أصيبت؟
She's fine.
إنها بخير.
But those assassins were the same ones from the Lantern Festival attack.
لكن هؤلاء القتلة كانوا نفسهم من هجوم مهرجان الفانوس.
They confessed that you were the mastermind
اعترفوا أنك كنت العقل المدبر
who orchestrated the attacks.
الذي دبر الهجمات.
You paid them off with the jade pendant
لقد دفعت لهم ثمن قلادة اليشم
to assassinate Xuanji during the Lantern Festival.
لاغتيال Xuanji خلال مهرجان الفوانيس.
I didn't want to make it public.
لم أكن أريد أن أجعلها علنية.
But Xuanji was in danger.
لكن Xuanji كان في خطر.
I reported to the authorities after I caught the assassins.
لقد أبلغت السلطات بعد أن ألقي القبض على القتلة.
Since there is solid proof, even I can't shield you.
وبما أن هناك دليل قوي، حتى أنا لا أستطيع حمايتك.
Master Zhaoxi, please come with us.
سيد تشاوشي، من فضلك تعال معنا.
Chaosheng, what's going on?
تشاوشينغ، ماذا يحدث؟
Zhaoxi lost his pendant when he was under attack.
فقد Zhaoxi قلادته عندما تعرض للهجوم.
If the assassins in Xuanji's courtyard carried that pendant,
إذا كان القتلة في فناء Xuanji حملت تلك القلادة،
doesn't that prove they're the same people?
لا يثبت ذلك إنهم نفس الأشخاص؟
They failed to kill him,
فشلوا في قتله،
so they're framing him.
لذا فهم يلقون التهمة عليه.
Don't you see what's happening, Chaosheng?
ألا ترى ماذا يحدث يا تشاوشينغ؟
Or...
أو...
What are you implying?
ماذا تقصد؟
The authorities will determine right and wrong.
ستقوم السلطات تحديد الصواب والخطأ.
If someone framed Zhaoxi, the authorities will clear his name.
إذا قام شخص ما بتأطير Zhaoxi، ستقوم السلطات بمسح اسمه.
He needs rest to recover from his injuries.
انه يحتاج الى الراحة للتعافي من إصاباته.
He's also a victim here.
وهو أيضًا ضحية هنا.
The two of us
نحن الإثنان
protected Xuanji from the assassins during the Lantern Festival gathering.
قام بحماية Xuanji من القتلة خلال تجمع مهرجان الفوانيس.
How could he be the mastermind?
كيف يمكن أن يكون العقل المدبر؟
Officers, please go back.
أيها الضباط، يرجى العودة.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Are you saying these officers won't do him justice?
هل تقول هؤلاء الضباط لن ينصفوه؟
My husband is frail and just survived an assassination.
زوجي ضعيف ونجا للتو من عملية اغتيال.
This trip would be too much for him.
هذه الرحلة ستكون أكثر من اللازم بالنسبة له.
Quit overthinking, Yuluo.
توقف عن التفكير الزائد، يولو.
Zhaoxi seems to be much better.
يبدو أن Zhaoxi أفضل بكثير.
If you keep obstructing this,
إذا واصلتم عرقلة هذا،
the authorities might start suspecting us.
السلطات قد يبدأ في الشك فينا.
Didn't you get what I meant?
لم تفهم قصدي؟
I meant to say that no one shall take anyone away
قصدت أن أقول أن لا يأخذ أحد أحدا
from the Fufeng Pavilion today.
من جناح فوفينج اليوم.
Don't worry. I'll be right back.
لا تقلق. سأعود حالا.
Master, do you need me to...
أستاذ هل تريدني أن...
Fetch my jewelry box. I'm going to the yamen.
أحضر صندوق مجوهراتي. انا ذاهب الى اليمن.
Understood.
مفهوم.
We'll interrogate the assassins.
سنقوم باستجواب القتلة.
I've spoken to the officers.
لقد تحدثت إلى الضباط.
They won't expose your identity.
لن يكشفوا هويتك.
That ledger ended up exactly where you predicted.
انتهى هذا الدفتر بالضبط حيث توقعت.
The Right Chancellor invited Princess Shang over right away.
المستشار المناسب دعت الأميرة شانغ على الفور.
But before Princess Shang even arrived,
ولكن قبل وصول الأميرة شانغ،
I had delivered the ledger to General Shen.
لقد قمت بتسليم دفتر الأستاذ للجنرال شين.
This is evidence of Princess Shang's crimes.
هذا دليل من جرائم الأميرة شانغ.
General Shen and some ministers impeached Princess Shang this morning.
الجنرال شين وبعض الوزراء عزل الأميرة شانغ هذا الصباح.
This time, she won't be able to turn the tide.
هذه المرة، لن تكون قادرة على قلب المد.
Were you spotted?
هل تم رصدك؟
Almost. Thankfully, I was quick-witted.
بالكاد. والحمد لله أنني كنت سريع البديهة.
That shadow clinging to your wife is relentless.
ذلك الظل التشبث بزوجتك لا هوادة فيه.
Right, the general asks when you plan to return.
صحيح، الجنرال يسأل عندما تخطط للعودة.
He suggests you send word back first
يقترح عليك إرسال الكلمة أولاً
and let that person know you're alright.
ودع هذا الشخص يعرف أنك بخير.
Also, those who went after the bandits returned.
وكذلك أولئك الذين ذهبوا بعد عودة قطاع الطرق.
The scouts said
قال الكشافة
that the bandits confessed to assassinating you and Gu Zhaoxi.
أن قطاع الطرق اعترفوا لاغتيالك أنت وGu Zhaoxi.
They said Gu Zhaoxi died on the spot.
قالوا إن Gu Zhaoxi مات على الفور.
(His body was dumped in a wolf pit)
(تم إلقاء جثته في حفرة الذئاب)
(and was gnawed down to bare bones.)
(وكان يقضم حتى العظام).
How's my uncle doing?
كيف حال عمي؟
He is in excellent health.
وهو بصحة ممتازة.
Master, when are you planning to return?
سيدي، متى تخطط للعودة؟
Aren't we doing fine here?
ألسنا بخير هنا؟
Please stop kidding, Master. This can't compare...
من فضلك توقف عن المزاح يا معلم. هذا لا يمكن مقارنته...
Y-You couldn't have fallen for...
ص-لا يمكن أن تقع في حب...
Zuixian Building's been overrun with dubious people.
لقد تم اجتياح مبنى Zuixian مع الناس المشكوك فيهم.
I might as well send you undercover as a male dancer.
ربما من الأفضل أن أرسلك متخفيًا كراقص ذكر.
Please don't. I'm sorry.
من فضلك لا تفعل ذلك. أنا آسف.
Speaking of your "wife",
بالحديث عن "زوجتك"،
I mean Gu Zhaoxi's wife...
أعني زوجة Gu Zhaoxi...
She brought a jewelry box to bail you out.
أحضرت صندوق مجوهرات لإنقاذك.
To avoid suspicion,
لتجنب الشبهة
I told those people to accept the bribe.
قلت لهؤلاء الناس أن يقبلوا الرشوة.
They'll "release" you because of that.
سوف "يطلقون سراحك" بسبب ذلك.
Where is she?
أين هي؟
Probably still outside the yamen.
ربما لا يزال خارج اليمن.
You're definitely into her.
أنت بالتأكيد معجب بها.
(Capital Yamen)
(عاصمة اليمن)
Dear.
عزيزي.
Didn't I tell you to wait at home?
ألم أخبرك أن تنتظر في المنزل؟
I was concerned.
كنت قلقا.
How long have you waited here?
كم من الوقت انتظرت هنا؟
Not long.
ليس طويلا.
I heard that you gave them
سمعت أنك أعطيتهم
a box of jewelry to bail me out.
علبة من المجوهرات لإنقاذي.
You were implicated because of me.
لقد تورطت بسببي.
I had to get you out, no matter what.
كان علي أن أخرجك مهما حدث.
Those trinkets mean nothing.
تلك الحلي لا تعني شيئاً
Every young lady cares about her jewels.
كل سيدة شابة تهتم بمجوهراتها.
They're only worldly possessions to me,
إنها مجرد ممتلكات دنيوية بالنسبة لي،
only useful for the Xuanji Pavilion's missions.
مفيدة فقط لمهمات Xuanji Pavilion.
Why did you bail me out?
لماذا قمت بكفالة لي؟
Your identity is fabricated.
هويتك ملفقة.
If they find out about it,
إذا علموا بذلك،
it may cause us trouble.
قد يسبب لنا المتاعب.
That's all?
هذا كل شيء؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
I thought you bailed me out because you couldn't bear
اعتقدت أنك أنقذتني لأنك لم تتحمل
to leave me suffering.
لتتركني أعاني.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Dear.
عزيزي.
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
You didn't even tend your wound.
أنت حتى لم تعالج جرحك
I'll do it myself later.
سأفعل ذلك بنفسي لاحقًا.
I applied your medicine last time.
لقد طبقت الدواء الخاص بك آخر مرة.
What's wrong now?
ما المشكلة الآن؟
Could it be
يمكن أن يكون
that you're shy?
أنك خجول؟
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
Very well. Let's proceed, dear.
جيد جدا. دعونا نمضي قدما، عزيزي.
♪Longing lingers within my heart♪
♪ الشوق باقي في قلبي ♪
♪Zither strings sigh for the sorrow parting♪
♪ تنهد أوتار آلة القانون لفراق الحزن ♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪ حكايات الماضي تعشعش في روحي ♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪ المودة باقية، لا تنسى ♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪ مخطوطات ملطخة بالحبر تذكر بما مضى ♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪ كل ضربة تحمل فكرة ♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪ الرخاء يتلاشى مثل الأحلام ♪
♪With nothing but memories left♪
♪ ولم يتبق سوى الذكريات ♪
How did you get that scar?
كيف حصلت على تلك الندبة؟
(Vast Mind, Eternal Will)
(العقل الواسع والإرادة الأبدية)
Master Wenshuang, you can't enter.
سيد وينشوانغ، لا يمكنك الدخول.
Wenshuang.
وينشوانغ.
Do you know what you're doing?
هل تعرف ماذا تفعل؟
He's not Zhaoxi. Zhaoxi is dead.
انه ليس تشاوكسي. تشاوشي مات.
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
Zhaoxi is dead.
تشاوشي مات.
The officers are back.
لقد عاد الضباط.
Those bandits confessed to every atrocity.
هؤلاء قطاع الطرق واعترف بكل فظاعة.
They stopped Zhaoxi's carriage and robbed him.
أوقفوا عربة Zhaoxi وسرقوه.
They then threw him into the wolf pit.
ثم ألقوا به في حفرة الذئب.
He was eaten alive by vicious wolves.
لقد أكلته الذئاب الضارية حياً.
The authorities are outside.
السلطات في الخارج.
The bandits confessed to assassinating you and Gu Zhaoxi.
اعترف قطاع الطرق لاغتيالك أنت وGu Zhaoxi.
They said Gu Zhaoxi died on the spot.
قالوا إن Gu Zhaoxi مات على الفور.
His body was dumped in a wolf pit
تم إلقاء جثته في حفرة الذئاب
and was gnawed down to bare bones.
وكان يقضم حتى العظام العارية.
This man is suspicious. He might have colluded with...
هذا الرجل مشبوه. ربما تواطأ مع...
Wenshuang.
وينشوانغ.
Where are the authorities?
أين السلطات؟
In the front hall.
في القاعة الأمامية.
You've exhausted yourself today. Stay and rest, dear.
لقد استنفدت نفسك اليوم. البقاء والراحة، يا عزيزي.
I'll be right back.
سأعود حالا.
Yuluo, are we leaving just like this?
يولو، هل سنغادر بهذه الطريقة؟
What if that imposter escapes?
ماذا لو هرب ذلك الدجال؟
Wenshuang, he is your third brother.
وينشوانغ، هو أخوك الثالث.
I brought him back. How could I be mistaken?
لقد أعادته. كيف يمكن أن أكون مخطئا؟
Exactly, you brought him back.
بالضبط، لقد أعادته.
Isn't the disguise technique
أليست تقنية التنكر
what you excel...
ما تتفوق...
Master Wenshuang, what are you implying?
سيد وينشوانغ، ماذا تقصد؟
Are you trying to say that I killed my husband?
هل تحاول أن تقول أنني قتلت زوجي؟
I never said that.
أنا لم أقل ذلك أبدا.
It's just that the Gu family isn't very close.
انها مجرد ذلك عائلة Gu ليست قريبة جدًا.
I grew up away from home.
لقد نشأت بعيدا عن المنزل.
Chaosheng travels for business.
يسافر تشاوشنغ للعمل.
Xuanji studies poison arts with the Medicine King.
يدرس Xuanji فنون السم مع ملك الطب.
Zhaoxi remained housebound due to chronic illness.
بقي Zhaoxi في المنزل بسبب مرض مزمن.
We met at Xuanji Pavilion as children.
التقينا في Xuanji Pavilion عندما كنا أطفالًا.
You know
هل تعلم
that I can try to be the family head if that's what you want.
أنه يمكنني أن أحاول أن أكون رب الأسرة إذا كان هذا هو ما تريد.
Master Wenshuang.
سيد وينشوانغ.
Since you're so straightforward,
بما أنك واضح جدًا،
let me make things clear.
اسمحوا لي أن أوضح الأمور.
I brought Zhaoxi back.
لقد أحضرت Zhaoxi مرة أخرى.
He's been traveling and staying with me.
لقد كان يسافر ويقيم معي.
How could I fail to tell if he's my husband?
كيف لا أستطيع أن أقول إذا كان زوجي؟
Master Wenshuang.
سيد وينشوانغ.
There has never been romance between us.
لم تكن هناك قصة حب بيننا قط.
I'm your third sister-in-law now.
أنا أخت زوجك الثالثة الآن.
It will remain this way forever.
وسيبقى الأمر على هذا النحو إلى الأبد.
♪Willows sway in the twilight breeze♪
♪ الصفصاف يتمايل في نسيم الشفق ♪
♪Ancient alleys guard time's secrets♪
♪ الأزقة القديمة تحرس أسرار الزمن ♪
♪Bluestones bear life's imprints♪
♪الأحجار الزرقاء تحمل بصمات الحياة♪
♪Falling petals, endless longing♪
♪ بتلات متساقطة، شوق لا نهاية له ♪
♪Longing lingers within my heart♪
♪ الشوق باقي في قلبي ♪
♪Zither strings sigh for the sorrow parting♪
♪ تنهد أوتار آلة القانون لفراق الحزن ♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪ حكايات الماضي تعشعش في روحي ♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪ المودة باقية، لا تنسى ♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪ مخطوطات ملطخة بالحبر تذكر بما مضى ♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪ كل ضربة تحمل فكرة ♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪ الرخاء يتلاشى مثل الأحلام ♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪ حكايات الماضي تعشعش في روحي ♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪ المودة باقية، لا تنسى ♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪ مخطوطات ملطخة بالحبر تذكر بما مضى ♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪ كل ضربة تحمل فكرة ♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪ الرخاء يتلاشى مثل الأحلام ♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪ حكايات الماضي تعشش في روحي ♪